Ahmad Samim Qeyam

Frontend Web Developer (JavaScript, React.js, HTML, CSS)

During my three years of professional work experience, I have built several high-impact web solutions for diverse industry organizations. I am skilled in designing, developing, and testing web-based applications and databases incorporating a range of technologies. Currently, I am aspiring to combine my background with my strong technical skills to excel as a Frontend Developer.

203 Heron Drive
Pittsburg, CA 94565
United States
(925)489-8605
ahmad.qeyam@gmail.com
LinkedIn/ahmad-samim-qeyam
Portfolio
GitHub/qeyamsamim

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Web Developer - Technical School of Innovation AUCA, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan. — *OCT 2021 - JUL 2023*

- Managed web development projects from initial design through completion, optimizing all cross-browser and multi-platform compatibility.
- Integrated a visually appealing chart with dynamic updates based on live data stream by using D3.js coupled with React.js, which increased reporting speed by 25%.
- Implemented a machine learning based product recommendation engine for a customer's e-commerce website that boosted their sales by 20%.

Frontend Web Developer - Fanoos Accounting Services, Kabul, Afghanistan. — *JUN 2021 - AUG 2021*

- Developed a new training and workshop management application with Angular and Firebase, which tripled the company's revenue generated through conducting workshops and training sessions.
- Implemented an efficient payroll management system, which reduced the time for payroll and HR related tasks by 35%.
- Enhanced and maintained the existing website of the company, which led to an increase of 37% in user engagement.

Full Stack Web Developer - Civil Society and Human Rights Network, Kabul, Afghanistan. — *JUN 2020 - MAY 2021*

- Improved website performance by 37% and reduced server cost by 20% through implementing Angular for frontend and Node.js in backend, and deploying the application on AWS.
- Expanded web capacity by 60% to handle 2k existing users by applying load balance with NGINX.
- Made employment management easier by designing a database schema and developing a local MySQL database.

EDUCATION

American University of Central Asia, Master of Arts in Business Administration. SEP 2021 – May 2023

American University of Central Asia, Bachelor of Software Engineering. SEP 2016 - MAY 2020

PROJECTS COMPLETED

- Fitness Website 2023
- E-commerce Website 2022
- Fanoos Training Management System 2021
- Fanoos Payroll Management System 2021
- Del Colosseo Web Application 2021

STACK

Proficient: JavaScript/ES6, React.js, Angular, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, REST API, Unit & E2E Testing, GitHub.

Familiar: Python, Web3.js, D3.js, AWS

AWARDS

Al Hackathon (2020), AUCA -My team received 2nd rank out of 15 teams.

Database Principles Course

2018) - Built school management system. Ranked 1st in the class. Received 2nd place in the regional competition.

LANGUAGES

Persian native
English C2, fluent
Russian B1, intermediate
German A2, beginner

INTERESTS

Design, Artificial Intelligence, Gaming, Reading, Creative Writing, Fitness, Soccer